Banks McLaurin, Jr. stereograph collection
DeGolyer Library
Banks McLaurin, Jr. stereograph collection
1851-1994
1851-1910
DeGolyer Library, Southern Methodist University
McLaurin, Banks, 1924-
14 Drawers, 28 Boxes (45.8 linear feet)
Banks McLaurin, Jr. (1924-2003) began collecting stereographs and 3-D materials after he retired from a career in the petroleum industry. His interests were broad, and the collection contains stereoscopic views by hundreds of photographers and publishers from the United States with some regional Texas, Louisiana, Oklahoma, Arkansas, and views by many foreign photographers. Specialized subjects include: agriculture, industry, humor, floral, world's fairs and expositions, political figures, and wars: the American Civil War, Spanish American War, World War I, World War II, Boer War, etc. Stereos are in such various formats as flat mounts, curved mounts, tissues, and chromolithographs. The collection includes boxed travel sets by Keystone, Underwood Underwood, H.C. White, and others, magic lantern slides, stereoscopes, View-Master and True-Vue viewers, and books.
Ag2000.1296
Biographical Note
Banks McLaurin, Jr. was born in Austin, Texas, on February 21, 1924, the son of Banks McLaurin, Sr. and Evelyn Davidson McLaurin. Mr. McLaurin fondly remembered looking through the family stereoscope at views as a boy in the same way children of later generations watched TV. He kept the viewer and about 135 views throughout his life. He graduated salutatorian from Austin High School in 1941. While at the University of Texas majoring in civil engineering, he joined the Navy ROTC. After he graduated in 1944, during World War II, he served aboard the USS Portland at Okinawa. He married Louise Cromwell Morrison and had three children, Candace Morrison McLaurin Volz, Thomas Banks McLaurin and Marion Glover McLaurin Forbes. Mr. McLaurin was a member of the Episcopal Church and an avid genealogist.
With a degree in engineering, McLaurin pursued a career in the field of petroleum first with Humble Oil Company, followed by thirty years with the Atlantic-Richfield Company. His father-in-law, who had one of the first home movie cameras in the 1920s, sparked his long-time interest in photography. McLaurin’s involvement in the medium evolved from making movies and slides to still photographs. After he retired, while he accompanied his wife to antique shops and shows, he thought he needed to collect something, too, and stereographs fit in with his photography interests and fondness for travel.
McLaurin loved the stereoscopic medium and collected from seemingly every category and time period. Although he enjoyed stereo’s virtual armchair travel, he and his wife frequently traveled abroad, where he also bought views for his collection. Banks McLaurin, Jr. died in Austin at the age of 79, November 17, 2003.
Sources:
"Banks McLaurin, Jr." Austin American Statesman, November 19, 2003.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Banks McLaurin, Jr. stereograph collection consists of approximately 9,000 stereographs, boxed travel sets, magic lantern slides, True-Vue reels, View-Master cards, 36 stereoscopes, viewers, a wooden stereo cabinet, books and back issues of Stereo World, ca. 1851-1930. The collection is arranged by state, country and subject. There are flat mount, curved mount, tissue and lithograph reproduction stereos (lithos) in the collection.
McLaurin collected in the following categories: American states, expositions, events, humor, people, foreign countries, war and disasters, agriculture, and industry. He collected approximately 9,000 stereo cards from a total of 106 countries. Besides views from around the world in various subject areas, he also sought stereos by different photographers, amassing views by roughly 800 image-makers. Some of his favorite stereos were the early, delicate French tissues.
McLaurin also acquired stereoscopes of all kinds, shapes and sizes, foreign and domestically produced, 36 in all from various time periods. He eventually branched out to include collecting later 3-D formats, Tru-Vue reels and View-Master cards and viewers as well. Because of the variety and depth of his stereo interests, the McLaurin collection mirrors and illustrates the history of the stereograph, world and social history and material culture from about 1851 to 1930. He carefully documented his stereos in a series of five notebooks leaving behind an impressive catalogue of his collection. Anxious to have his stereographs and viewers available to the public, he generously donated his collection to the DeGolyer Library at Southern Methodist University in 2000.
In Series I through 14, there are no listings of individual stereographs in the finding aid, but there are inventories in Notebook III. Some individual stereo titles are listed in Series 15 through 18. No updating of spelling or place names was done. In the boxed sets, some stereos have two numbers for a single view, one in front of the title which is a negative number and sometimes one in the middle at the top of the card for the number of the view in the series. Sometimes the copyright date is also noted as "c." on the mount and title list.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into 19 series:
Series 1: United States Views
Series 2: Foreign Views
Series 3: Expositions
Series 4: Military
Series 5: Transportation
Series 6: U.S. States Oversize
Series 7: Agriculture, Animals, Astronomy and Industry
Series 8: Children
Series 9: Christian Religion and Still Life
Series 10: Genre, Courtship, and Domestic
Series 11: Genre and Comic
Series 12: People and U.S. Presidents
Series 13: Tissues and Special Formats
Series 14: Lithographs
Series 15: Small Boxed Sets
Series 16: Boxed Travel Sets
Series 17: Stereoscopes, True-Vue and View-Master Viewers, and Magic Lantern Projectors
Series 18: Magic Lantern Slides
Series 19: McLaurin Notebooks
Related Materials
There are many other stereograph collections in the DeGolyer Library.
Access to Collection:
Collection is open for research use.
Access Terms
This collection is indexed under the following terms in the Southern Methodist University Libraries' online catalog. Researchers desiring related materials may search the catalog using these terms.
Stereographs; Tissue stereographs; Lantern slides; Stereoscopes; Stereoscopic views.; Stereoscopic cameras.
Acquisition Information
Gift, Banks McLaurin, Jr., 2000, 2003.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- United States Views, Series 1:
  - Alabama to Hawaii (Drawer 1)
  - Idaho to Nevada (Drawer 2)
  - New Hampshire to New York City (Drawer 3)
  - New York, Niagara Falls to Texas (Drawer 4)
  - Utah to Wyoming (Drawer 5)
- Foreign Views, Series 2:
  - Aden, Algeria, Antarctic, Australia, Austria, Bahamas, Belgium, Belgium Congo, Bermuda, Bolivia, Brazil, Bulgaria, Burma, Cambodia, Canada, Ceylon, Chile, China, Columbia, Cuba, Czechoslovakia, Denmark, Dominican Republic, Ecuador (Drawer 6)
  - Egypt, El Salvador, San Salvador, England, Fiji, Finland, France (Drawer 7)
  - France, Germany, Gibraltar, Greenland, Guam, Guatemala, Honduras, Hong Kong, Hungary, Iceland, India, Indonesia, Iraq, Ireland, Israel (Drawer 8)
  - Italy, Jamaica, Japan, Java, Kenya, Korea, Lapland, Lebanon, Luxemburg, Malaysia, Mexico, Monaco, Morocco, Mozambique, Netherlands, New Guinea, New Zealand, Nicaragua, Nigeria (Drawer 9)
  - Norway, Palestine, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Philippines Islands, Poland, Porto Rico, Portugal, Romania, Russia, Singapore, South Africa, Spain (Drawer 10)
  - Scotland, Sudan, Sweden, Switzerland, Syria, Thailand, Tanzania, Turkey, Uganda, Ukraine, Uruguay, Venezuela, Wales, West Indies, Yugoslavia (Drawer 11)
- Expositions, Series 3:
  - Crystal Palace Exhibition, London 1851; International Exhibition of 1862, London; Exposition Universelle, Paris 1867; The First Annual Exhibition, London 1871; Centennial Exposition, Philadelphia 1876; World’s Columbian Exposition, Chicago 1893; California Midwinter International Exposition of 1894, San Francisco 1894; Trans-Mississippi and International Exposition, Omaha 1898. World’s Fair of 1900, Paris 1900; Pan-American Exposition, Buffalo 1901; Louisiana Purchase Exposition, Saint Louis 1904; 1902 Toronto; 1906 Portland; Jamestown Exposition, Hampton Roads 1907; Panama Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco 1915. (Drawer 12)
- Military, Series 4:
  - Boar War (1899–1902), Civil War (1861-1865), China Opium War (1839 to 1842), Russo-Japanese War (1904-1905), Spanish-American War (1898), Turkish-Italian War (1911), World War I (1914-1918) (Drawer 13)
- Transportation, Series 5:
  - Airplanes, Railroads, Roads/Auto, Ships, and Naval Ships (Drawer 14)
- U.S. States Oversize, Series 6:
  - U.S. – Arizona to Missouri (Oversize Stereos) (Box 1)
  - U.S. – Montana to Wyoming (Oversize Stereos) (Box 2)
- Agriculture, Animals, Astronomy and Industry, Series 7:
  - Agriculture and Industry, Astronomy, Flower and Plants, Flower Arrangements, Animals and Birds (Box 3)
- Children, Series 8:
  - Children, Children with Animals (sometimes humorous) (Box 4)
- Christian Religion and Still Life, Series 9:
  - Scenes of the Life of Christ, Christ Passion, Christmas, Still-Life, Skeleton Leaves (death memorial series), Statuary, and Sad Situations (illness, death) (Box 5)
- Genre, Courtship and Domestic, Series 10:
  These are often humorous. Many are series and as such precursors to motion pictures.
  - Courtship and Marriage (sometimes tongue in cheek humorous series), French Cook Series (husband being amorous with the young attractive cook), Gossip (women talking together), Halloween Party, Mouse and Rat Series, and the New Woman (women riding bicycles, asserting themselves with men, telling men to sew their own clothes, etc.). (Box 6)
- Genre and Comic, Series 11:
  - Comic Situations, Humor, Hunting, Fishing, (sometimes humorous) and Sports (Box 7)
- People and U.S. Presidents, Series 12:
  - People, Blacks (often making fun of African Americans), Indians, U.S. Presidents, Photographica, and People with Stereo Viewers (Box 8)
- Tissues and Special Formats, Series 13:
  - Europe, Genre, Cortescopes, Cavender’s Camerascope, Real Photographs, and Small Format Stereo (Box 9)
- Stereo Lithographs, Series 14:
  - U.S. and Foreign Lithographs, Courtship, Genre, and Humor (Box 10)
- Small Boxed Sets, Series 15:
  - Keystone View Co. [eye comfort series] The Keystone Eye Comfort and Depth Perception Series. For the Development of Comfortable Vision and a High Degree of Depth Perception. Stereos labeled B0 1 BI 1, BI 2. (Box 11)
    - EC 1 V32929 Man in chair
    - EC 2 V32930 Man in chair
    - EC 3 V32931 Man in chair
    - EC 4 V32932 Man in chair
    - EC 6 32934 Polar bear and baby calf
    - EC 7 32935 Man and squirrel
    - EC 9 32937 Landscape and birds
    - EC 10 Landscape
    - EC 107 (33288) Ship and squirrel
    - EC 229 (35227) Man and boat
  - Kroll’s Stereoscopical Pictures for the use of squint-eyed people. Stereos labeled 1 through 30. Stereos are for children with squinting eyes.
  - Humor. Set of 12 stereos describing the humorous conflict between an artist and a musician.
    - 925 McDaub finishing his picture
    - 926 He dreams of Honduras
    - 927 Signor Tempestnoss
    - 928 McDaub awakened
    - 929 Anathematizing
    - 930 Prepares for vengeance
    - 931 A squirt through the wall
    - 932 McDaub congratulates himself
    - 933 The Signors room
    - 934 Determined on revenge
    - 935 Meeting in the studio
    - 936 The battle of the two arts
  - Sears, Roebuck Co. – 50 stereos of Sears headquarters in Chicago of the operations: accounting, administration, dining, president, switchboard, railroad, etc.
  - Japan and Russian Views. 48 Assorted Photocolortypes of architectural, occupational and topographical views of Japan and Russia.
  - Foreign Stereographs and Lithographs. Set of 25 stereographs of odd sights and scenes from foreign countries numbering 101 to 125, dated 1925, American Colortype (A.C.).
  - World Series. Set of 46 stereo lithographs, copyright 1905, Kawin and Co., mainly architectural and landscape images, numbering from 115 to 291 with many missing numbers.
- Boxed Travel Sets, Series 16:
  - Journey in the Holy Land, Through the Perfecscope (2 identical sets of views), Underwood Underwood. Stereos in the box are the first set of 100 views of Palestine and the Holy Land, which includes architectural, occupational and topographical images. (Box 12)
  - Egypt and Its Wonders: Through the Perfecscope. Stereos in the box are not of Egypt, but rather a duplicate set of the 100 views listed above of Palestine and the Holy Land, which includes architectural, occupational and topographical images.
  - Keystone View Co., Tour of the World, Foreign # 1 to 299 (Box 13)
  - Keystone View Co., Tour of the World, Foreign # 302 to 698 (Box 14)
  - Keystone View Co., Tour of the World, Foreign # 700 to 1038 (Box 15)
  - Keystone View Co., Tour of the World, Foreign, US and Canada # 1039 to 1200 (Box 16)
  - Stereographic Library, Tour of the World, empty boxes for above boxes 13 to 16 (Box 17)
  - Boxed Sets (Box 18)
    - British Isles, Vol. I, Vol. II, Stereographic Library. Set of 100 with 6, 12, 73 missing. Bought 1990 at Unlimited, Ltd., The Antique Mall on Midway Rd., Dallas.
      - 1 25404 London Bridge from Surrey Side
      - 2 13113 The Great Tower Bridge
      - 3 28249 The Thames Embankment, London
      - 4 28226 The Bank of England
      - 5 28250 below Temple Bar, London
      - 6 Missing
      - 7 25482 Old Curiosity Shop London
      - 8 28105 Traffic on high Holburn St., London
      - 9 28101 The Strand, London
      - 10 25423 Law Courts, London
      - 11 28253 Trafalgar Square, London
      - 12 Missing
      - 13 V-13196 Houses of Parliament across the Thames
      - 14 11312 Entrance of the House of Lords
      - 15 11311 The House of Commons
      - 16 V-25486 Westminster Abbey
      - 17 V-18170 Buckingham Palace
      - 18 28254 Terrace of Richmond Park
      - 19 28104 In the Rockeries, Kew Gardens, Surrey Co.
      - 20 28255 Scene in Kew Gardens, Surrey Co.
      - 21 13134 Windsor Castle, Windsor
      - 22 W-28244 Norman Gateway, Windsor Castle
      - 23 W-28256 Gray's Elegy Scene, Stoke Poges
      - 24 28257 Old Almshouses built by Queen Victoria, Whippingham
      - 25 28258 Colored Chalk Cliffs, Isle of Wight
      - 26 28259 Bar Gate, High St., Southampton
      - 27 28260 Pilgrim Fathers Memorial, Southampton
      - 28 28261 Chained books, Minister Library, Wimborne
      - 29 28262 St. Anne's Gateway, Salisbury
      - 30 28212 Salisbury Cathedral
      - 31 28203 Market in Salisbury
      - 32 13158 Stonehenge, Wiltshire
      - 33 3025 Abbey Church, Bath
      - 34 V-28187 Glastonbury Abbey
      - 35 V-28186 Exeter Cathedral
      - 36 28264 Drake's Island, Plymouth
      - 37 28265 War Drake Memorials, Plymouth
      - 38 28266 Royal Albert Bridge, Plymouth
      - 39 28267 Smeaton's Lighthouse, Plymouth
      - 40 V-28268 Interior, Truro Cathedral
      - 41 V-25440 Perranporth – Rugged Coast
      - 42 V-28269 St. Michael's Mount, Cornwall
      - 43 V-25405 Land's End
      - 44 28270 Water tower
      - 45 W-28206 Chester Cathedral, Chester
      - 46 W-28500 Carnarvon Castle, Wales
      - 47 28271 Main Entrance, Conway Castle, Wales
      - 48 2705 Pont y Pais, Betws-y-Coed, Wales
      - 49 28272 View of Landing Stage, Liverpool
      - 50 28273 Landing Stage, Liverpool
      - 51 28274 Queen Victoria Statue, Liverpool
      - 52 28275 St. John's Gardens, Liverpool
      - 53 28276 Ranelagh St., Liverpool
      - 54 28277 City Hall, Manchester
      - 55 V-13190 Furness Abbey, Lancashire
      - 56 V-15452 Church of Rydal, Lake District
      - 57 13123 Wadsworth's home, Lake District
      - 58 V-25450 Borrowdale Valley, Lake District
      - 59 V-25449 Derwentwater, Lake District
      - 60 13116 Langdale Valley, Lake District
      - 61 V-28278 Dungeon Gill Waterfall, Lake District
      - 62 V-25474 Stybarrow Crag
      - 63 28279 Swing Bridge, New Castle-on-Tyne
      - 64 28280 Northumberland St., New Castle-on-Tyne
      - 65 28281 Market place, New Castle-on-Tyne
      - 66 V-13191 Cathedral nave, Durham
      - 67 28282 York Minister
      - 68 28283 Old Walls, York
      - 69 3018 St. Mary's Abbey, York
      - 70 28284 War memorial, Sheffield
      - 71 28285 Cutlery Plant, Sheffield
      - 72 28286 Market Place, Nottingham
      - 73 Missing
      - 74 28288 Chatsworth, near Derby
      - 75 28289 East Gate Clock Tower, Leicester
      - 76 28290 Gallowtree Gate, Leicester
      - 77 28188 Interior View, Litchfield Cathedral
      - 78 28291 L.M.S. Station, Birmingham
      - 79 28292 Town Hall, Birmingham
      - 80 28293 City Hall, Birmingham
      - 81 V-28176 Warwick Castle
      - 82 28162 Kenilworth Castle
      - 83 28294 Shakespeare's Birth Place, Stratford-upon-Avon
      - 84 W-28300 Living room of Shakespeare's Home, Stratford-upon-Avon
      - 85 W-28301 Resting Place of Shakespeare, Stratford-upon-Avon
      - 86 28295 Anne Hathaway’s Cottage, Stratford-upon-Avon
      - 87 V-25407 Shakespeare's memorial theater, Stratford upon-Avon
      - 88 V-25409 Addison's Walk, Oxford
      - 89 V-25465 King's College, Oxford
      - 90 V-25467 Bridge of Sighs, Cambridge
      - 91 V-28184 Ely Cambridge – Interior
      - 92 V-28296 Blickling Hall, Norfolk
      - 93 V-28190 Peterborough Cathedral
      - 94 V-28297 Gothic Interior, St. Botolph's, Boston
      - 95 V-28298 Lincoln Cathedral – Interior
      - 96 V-28168 Arundel Castle
      - 97 25427 Brighton – on the beach
      - 98 V-28175 Gate of Battle Abbey, Sussex
      - 99 V-13177 Canterbury Cathedral – Interior
      - 100 28299 Moonlight on the English Channel
    - Grand Canyon, Vol. 1, Stereographic Library. Keystone View Co. Set of 18 in box with a descriptive book with maps, The Grand Canyon of the Arizona Through the Stereoscope by Underwood Underwood. All copyrighted by U U – date of publication ca. 1900. Bought at Gainesville Antique Mall on 12/13/91.
      - (1) 6072 A Wonder to the primitive inhabitants – Santa Fe Train crossing Cañon Diablo, AZ
      - (2) 6073 From the Red to San Francisco Mountain – A Woody Wilderness in AZ
      - (3) 6074 Blown asunder by volcanic energies – Red Mountain, AZ
      - (4) 6075 Labyrinthine ways through the lava ash formation Red. Mt. Crater, AZ
      - (5) 6076 The sinuous Colorado, yellow as the Tiber, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (6) 6077 Among the buttes, Red Canon Trail, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (7) 6078 Fathoming the depth of a vanished sea – Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (8) 6079 Descending into Grand View Trail, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (9) 6080 Diacritic stalagmites in a limestone cave, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (10) 6081 Angel’s Gateway and Newberry Terrance from Cottonwood Spring, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (11) 6082 Beside the Colorado – looking up to Zoroaster Tower from Pipe Cr., Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (12) 6083 Down the Granite Gorge, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (13) 6084 Prospecting for gold, Indian gardens, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (14) 6085 Rounding Cape Horn on Bright Angel Trail, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (15) 6086 Thos. Moran, America’s great scenic artist, sketching at Bright Angel Cover, AZ
      - (16) 6087 Over all broods a solemn silence – sunset at O’Neill’s Point, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (17) 6088 Overlooking Nature’s greatest Amphitheatre, from Rowe’s Point, NW, Grand Cañon, AZ
      - (18) 6089 On the brink, one mile above the River, Grand Cañon, AZ west from Rowe’s Point
    - Holland. Underwood Underwood. Set of 17 stereos on Holland in case, c. 1904.
      - Quaint houses, bridges fishing boats, Hoorn
      - Everyday business on a canal, Volendam
      - Groningen, St. Martin’s Kerk and University Museum
      - Looking up canal to old weigh house, Amsterdam
      - Weigh House and Market, Hoorn
      - Busy Leuvehaven, north to fish market Groote Kerk, Rotterdam
      - From Zeider Kerk over Weigh house to suburbs, Amsterdam
      - Voorburgwal reflecting St. Nicholas Church, Amsterdam
      - Market and Weigh House, Nymegen
      - Church at Delfthaven where Pilgrim Fathers prayed
      - Windmill on Dyke road west of Dordrecht
      - Countrywomen with milk pails, Goes, Zealand
      - Fishing boats at pier, Helder
      - East across the Oudehaven with its shipping bridges, Rotterdam
      - Tree lined canal north to Zuider Kerk, Amsterdam
      - Southeast from Zuider Kerk, Amsterdam
      - Hugh Windmills at Zandyk
    - Java. Underwood Underwood. Set of 36 stereos in a box for 36, c. 1907
      - 9063 The Cathedral at Batavia
      - 9064 Pier at Tandjong, Priock, from steamer’s deck, arrival at Batavia, capital of Java
      - 9065 Molenfleit canal and the North Walk, principal European thoroughfare of Batavia
      - 9066 "North Walk" and its picturesque Melenfleit Canal, Batavia
      - 9067 Gang Patganongen, an important street in the Chinese District of Batavia
      - 9068 One of the many public laundries along the banks of the Melenfleit Canal, Batavia
      - 9069 A morning bath in the Melenfleit Canal, Batavia
      - 9070 Koenigs Plein (King’s Place), a public square in Batavia
      - 9071 Bellevue Hotel, shaded by palms, at Buitenzorg, the enchanting mountain Resort in Java
      - 9072 From Hotel Bellevue, Buitenzorg s.w. over forests of coconut palms to Mt. Salak
      - 9073 Palace of the Governor-General, within the botanical gardens, Buitenzorg
      - 9073 Looking down the main street of Buitenzorg, to Bellevue Hotel – canary trees on walk
      - 9075 Street Market – foreground are "durians," one of the most noted of fruits, Buitenzorg
      - 9076 Avenue of canary trees covered with gigantic creepers, Botanical Garden, Buitenzorg
      - 9077 Lily pond and banyan tree at Buitenzorg Botanical Garden
      - 9078 Deer on the botanical gardens of Buitenzorg
      - 9079 Maze of roots and old decayed trunk of a banyan tree in the botanical garden of Buitenzorg
      - 9080 The big leafed Victoria Regia, and the curious "Sausage" tree, Botanical Gardens, Buitenzorg
      - 9081 Screw pines in the Botanical Gardens, Buitenzorg
      - 9082 Luxuriant palms in the finest Botanical Gardens in the world
      - 9083 Javanese, the native inhabitants of eastern Java near Villadolce Hotel, Garoet
      - 9084 A band of alang-alang player, an ancient instrument of natives of Garoet
      - 9085 Soldiers crossing a stream during maneuvers – flooded rice fields in foreground, Garoet
      - 9086 Natives fishing in the low waters of a pond, Garoet
      - 9087 Native vendors, ragged and dirty, awaiting arrival of the train, Brambanum
      - 9088 The outdoor market, on roadway leading to the noted Temples, Brambanum
      - 9089 A world famed example of Hindu art – temples of Brambanum
      - 9090 Temple of Loro Jonggran 9th century Bramantic temple at Brambanum
      - 9091 Loro Junggran "the pure exalted virgin" to whom the temples of Brambanum are dedicated
      - 9092 "The three graces" – a far-famed sculpture in the great temples of Brambanum
      - 9093 Boro Boedor – the most remarkable and magnificent monument Buddhism has ever erected
      - 9094 A section of the three miles of sculptures – picture bible of Buddhism, Boro Boedur Temple
      - 9095 Latticed shrines and central dome on top of the remarkable temple of Boro Boedor
      - 9096 One of the hundreds of statues of Buddha at the great temple of Boro Boedor
      - 9097 An avenue of trees leading north from the temple of Boro Boedor
      - 9098 Looking over the tropical fields of Java from the summit of Boro Boedor Temple